Right this way.
這邊請
They're here.
他們到了
Dr. Nishizaki. Welcome to Tojo University Hospital.
西崎教授，歡迎來到東城大學
Thank you for your warm welcome, Dr. Saeki.
感謝您前來迎接我們，佐伯教授
We look forward to working with you in the coming weeks
我們期待接下來幾星期與貴院合作
and we appreciate your cooperation.
還請務必配合我們
The pleasure is all mine.
您太客氣了
Let's work together and ensure a smooth operation.
我們一定要互相配合，讓手術成功
Two universities with zero interest in cooperating.
完全沒有任何合作意願的兩所大學
Why did this happen in the first place?
為什麼會彼此協助？
Just one week prior…
這件事還得從一星期前說起
ONE WEEK EARLIER
（一星期前）
Japan Surgical Journal editor-in-chief Mr. Ikenaga
《日本外科雜誌》的池永主編
paid us a visit along with Dr. Nishizaki.
跟西崎教授一同前來拜訪我們醫院
A reveal event for the Caesar?
您是說凱撒機器人的發布會？
As I'm sure you've heard,
想必您聽說了
the next Surgical Society summit will be hosted by Teika University.
下一屆外科醫學會大會 將由帝華大學主辦
As the centerpiece of our research announcement,
作為此次研究的核心主題
I would like to reveal the final operation of the Caesar's clinical trial.
我打算公開國產凱撒機器人 臨床試驗的最後一次手術
However, the Caesar is currently at Tojo University.
但是，凱撒目前在東城大學
Even if you wish to reveal it--
即使您想要公開恐怕也…
The operation will be performed at Tojo
只要把在東城大學進行的手術
and broadcast live to the event venue at Teika University.
實況轉播到帝華大學的會場就行了
The Japan-made Darwin is receiving attention from around the world.
這款國產達爾文在全世界備受矚目
We at the Japan Surgical Journal
我們《日本外科雜誌》
would be thrilled to report on this operation.
也非常期待報導這次的手術
I see. That would be quite a large-scale experiment.
原來如此，這可是一項大規模的試驗
Very well. You have my blessing.
那好吧，我們沒有意見
I'm glad to hear it.
那真是太好了
The operating surgeon will be Dr. Takashina or Dr. Kurosaki.
那麼就由高階或者黑崎來執刀
I would personally like to entrust the operation to Dr. Sakaguchi
我個人屬意交由坂口醫生來執刀
who is leading the Caesar research at Teika University.
他在我們帝華大學 長期主持凱撒的研究計畫
I would like Teika University to spearhead this operation.
希望這次手術 能由我們帝華大學來主導
What do you think, Dr. Saeki?
佐伯教授，您意下如何？
Very well.
可以
-Well then. -In that case,
-很好 -這樣的話
I would like you to operate, Dr. Nishizaki.
務必由西崎教授您來執刀
Me?
我嗎？
This is a monumental operation
這是一次具有里程碑意義的手術
that will mark the completion of the Caesar.
代表凱撒的研發圓滿落幕
The operation should be done by the man leading that research.
執刀醫生自然也得由研究的領導人
That man is you, Dr. Nishizaki.
也就是西崎教授您來擔任吧
If that sounds too difficult for you,
如果您有難處的話
then I would like to ask one of my own men at Tojo, as usual.
那麼能不能還是照慣例 交由我們東城大學執刀呢？
Understood.
好吧
Let's do it.
那就這麼辦
Dr. Nishizaki is operating at last.
終於輪到西崎教授出馬了
This is exciting.
真令人期待
Yes, it sure is.
可不是嗎？
Dr. Saeki waited until the last second to deliver the blow.
佐伯那傢伙居然在最後一刻擺我一道
It might be for the best.
這未嘗不是好事
If you complete the operation,
如果由您完成手術
it could greatly benefit you in the election.
對理事長選舉將大有助益
It would virtually guarantee your victory.
您已經穩操勝券了
That is true.
這倒是真的
I look forward to the day of the surgery.
期待您那天的手術
I'll see you off.
我送您
But if we fail,
不過要是失敗
it will all be for nothing.
一切都會白費了
We'll now perform on-pump, on-beat mitral valve surgery.
接下來進行 體外循環自主心跳二尖瓣手術
-Let's begin. -Yes, sir.
-開始吧 -拜託您了
For better or for worse,
無論如何
this operation will decide everything.
這次的手術將會決定一切
That's why, for Teika's good name,
正因為如此，為了帝華大學的名聲
I will ensure a successful operation.
我會確保手術成功
Right.
是
Thus ends the age of the scalpel.
這樣一來 使用手術刀的時代就要終結了
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -是
-Metz.
-手術剪 -這裡
-Dr. Saeki is really amazing. -The professor is great,
-佐伯教授好厲害 -教授當然厲害
but Nurse Fujiwara keeping up is incredible too.
但能跟上教授速度的藤原護理長 也很了不起
They've been working together for over 20 years.
聽說他們已經搭檔二十多年了
-That long? -They're closer than a married couple.
-這麼久了？ -關係比夫妻更緊密
We'll remove the valve tip. Scalpel.
接下來切除瓣尖，手術刀
Here.
是
What?
怎麼回事？
I'm sorry, it was my mistake.
對不起，是我的過失
I was late preparing the instruments. Please forgive me.
是我遞太慢了，真的很抱歉
-Continue the procedure. -Okay.
-繼續進行手術 -是
Scalpel.
手術刀
-Metz. -Here.
-手術剪 -這裡
So it was the nurse's fault? What a joke.
手術室護理師出錯？真是笑話
I would have preferred to see Dr. Saeki mess up himself.
如果是佐伯自己出錯，那就有趣了
It was a close call, but it seems like they're okay.
雖然有點出包，不過好像沒什麼問題
Did the head nurse really make a mistake?
剛才真的是護理長的失誤嗎？
-What? -I guess not.
-什麼？ -我猜不是
The problem is the patient.
患者才是關鍵
Takashina, do you understand why I sent you to infiltrate Tojo?
高階，我把你安插在這裡的原因
Well?
你知道嗎？
Yes.
知道
I will find a patient with mild issues to ensure there is a low risk of failure.
您要我找一個問題不大 能確保手術失敗率低的患者
Someone perfect for our big reveal.
作為發表會的病例
I'm counting on you.
那就靠你了
Soon after,
不久
details of the Caesar reveal event were shared with everyone.
凱撒發布會的細項也對全院公布了
The operating team will include members from Tojo.
東城大學也要派人加入手術團隊
Any volunteers?
有誰自願嗎？
-We'd be just assistants, right? -Exactly.
-我們也只能當助手吧? -沒錯
This operation is for Teika's sake, isn't it?
這場手術到頭來 不就是為了帝華大學嗎？
Why do we have to help our enemy?
為什麼要協助對手啊？
It's a done deal.
事情已經塵埃落定了
I'll join the team.
我願意加入
I have the most experience doing surgeries with the Caesar.
比起其他人 我用凱撒動手術有更豐富的經驗
All right then. Thank you.
那就麻煩你了
Anyone else?
還有人要加入嗎？
-You have experience, don't you Dr. Sera? -No, they don't need me.
-世良醫生，你也有經驗吧？ -他們不需要我啦
Then I'll do it.
那就我來吧
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生…
You too.
你也來
Huh?
什麼？
What is this about?
什麼意思？
I'll be joining the Caesar team.
我加入凱撒團隊
Five days before the Caesar reveal event,
凱撒發布會登場的前五天
the Teika team arrived at Tojo for preparations.
帝華大學的團隊 來到東城大學進行術前準備
Let's get started with the preparations at once.
那我們立刻著手準備吧
Right.
好
Please use our facilities freely until the day of the surgery.
手術前 各位可以自由使用外科部門的設施
-Show them around. -Right. This way, please.
-帶他們去認識環境 -是，這邊請
Please excuse me for a moment.
我失陪一下
Wait, what about Teika?
那帝華大學的人怎麼辦？
Let them do whatever they want.
隨他們去吧
-Hey, that's my desk! -What are you doing?
-那是我的桌子 -你們幹嘛？
We were given permission to use this room as we please.
我們得到許可 可以自由使用這個辦公室
Where are we supposed to work?
那我們去哪裡工作？
You're free to work over there.
你們可以去那邊做事
It's so cramped!
好擠
Look at that. It's the simulation Caesar.
你們看，是凱撒的模擬器
If they have all those things,
既然有那麼方便的東西
they should have lent it to us in the first place!
應該一開始就借給我們
Dr. Sakaguchi.
坂口
Yes.
是
We'll be holding a meeting.
我們要開會了
I would like you all to leave.
請你們離開
What?
什麼？
Thank you for your cooperation.
感謝合作
What the hell is going on? This is our office.
搞什麼啊？明明是我們的辦公室
The professor gave them permission.
是教授同意的
Yeah, but this is taking it too far.
但這也太過分了
Regarding the crucial element, our patient…
關於最重要的患者
Tojo University has selected three candidates for us to choose from.
東城大學選出三位候選人
All three of them are severe cases.
三人都是重症病例啊
As expected, they've chosen difficult candidates on purpose.
不出所料，故意挑了棘手的患者
We will choose a candidate
至於選擇哪個患者
after we have finished examining each one.
要等手術前一天的檢查結果出爐後 再做決定
Dr. Nishizaki will be operating.
執刀醫生是西崎教授
Dr. Takashina and I will be assisting.
我和高階醫生擔任助手
-As far as the rest of the team… -You take forever.
-至於其他工作人員 -廢話一堆
Dr. Nishizaki. You plan on making this operation a success, right?
西崎教授，你很希望手術成功吧？
-Of course, I do. -In that case, your assistant…
-那當然 -既然這樣，那助手…
Dr. Tokai, please. Excuse me.
渡海醫生，抱歉
Me and this guy. We don't need anyone else getting in our way.
就我跟他，不需要其他人礙事
Any patient is fine by me.
患者選誰都行啊
You'll be fine if I'm there.
有我在就沒問題
It will succeed no matter who operates.
無論誰執刀都能成功
Lucky for you.
算你走運
Dr. Nishizaki.
西崎教授
What's that?
你說什麼？
There's one more person I've asked to help.
我還要叫上一個人
I'm Nekota. An operating nurse.
我是擔任手術室護理師的貓田
Congratulations.
恭喜啊
Chairman Nishizaki.
西崎理事長
Nekota is on the team too?
連貓田護理師都加入手術團隊了嗎？
Dr. Tokai seems to be taking things seriously this time.
是的，渡海醫生這次比以往更認真
Still,
不過
up until now, he never showed any interest in the newest equipment.
直到現在 渡海醫生一直對新器械興趣缺缺
You're right.
確實是
Why is Dr. Tokai acting like he wants to help Teika?
渡海醫生為什麼要幫帝華大學的忙？
Of course, the patient's life is our top priority.
當然，一切以救人為先
We're hoping for a successful operation.
所以希望凱撒手術成功
But there's also the election.
不過，這還牽涉到理事長競選
Perhaps Dr. Tokai is hoping for my failure.
渡海他期待看到我失敗是嗎？
That could be said as well.
也許可以這麼說
Whatever it may be, there's no one else we can rely on.
無論如何，現在也只能仰賴他了
I'll be back.
我出去一趟
What about the medical safety meeting?
待會還要開醫療安全會議
Do it without me.
不必等我了
The doctor has been out a lot recently.
教授最近經常外出
Without him here, there's no stopping Teika.
沒有他坐鎮 帝華大學就會無法無天了
They'll take over completely.
他們一定會接管一切
After that,
之後
simulations of the operation
針對即將到來的手術
were held leading up to the big day.
展開一連串的模擬手術
-Okay, follow me. -Right.
-好，跟著我 -是
How many times has he used the Caesar?
那傢伙到底做過多少次凱撒手術了？
It's his first time touching it.
這是他第一次使用
Artificial valve ring placement complete.
人工瓣膜環置換完成
-4-0, please. -Right.
-4-0縫線 -是
Okay, Great Doctor.
那麼大醫生
You're up.
接下來麻煩你了
Right.
好
Complete.
完成
A job well done, as is to be expected.
果然一如預期，太棒了
Well. You too.
你也是
And you as well. You have quite the skills.
你也一樣，技術精湛
You too, Great Doctor.
彼此彼此，大醫生
Let's repeat this success during the real surgery as well.
等到正式手術時，也要馬到成功
This is Teika's big reveal event.
這可是帝華大學主導的發布會
Will you just stand there sucking your thumbs?
你們就在旁邊乾瞪眼嗎？
Get me the exam data of the three candidate patients.
快去替候選的三名患者做檢查
Yes!
是
You're being quite cooperative this time.
你這次還真是配合
You had us good last time.
之前我們被你耍了好幾次
What were you unhappy about?
你到底有什麼不滿嗎？
You didn't have a good rice cooker.
沒有像樣的電鍋啊
That reminds me.
我突然想起來
When you left Teika,
你離開帝華的時候
a man from our hospital named Dr. Takeda left as well.
我們醫院一個叫武田的醫師也離開了
I'll leave it then.
那我就不計較了
But instead, give me that.
不過，把那樣東西給我吧
We found traces of someone using his ID card
我們發現有人用武田的帳密
to access Teika's main computer system.
進入帝華大學的電腦系統
What confuses me is the nature of the access.
查詢的內容讓我們很困惑
Out of the more than 100 nationwide hospitals connected to Teika,
我們在國內的100多家相關院所中
they were searching for one particular patient.
對方特別查詢一位病患的資料
I-I-N
（飯）
The name Tatsuji Iinuma was searched.
那個人查詢飯沼達次這個名字
Tatsuji Iinuma?
飯沼達次？
However, the search returned zero results.
但查詢沒有結果
Unfortunately, that patient doesn't seem to be in any of our hospitals.
很遺憾，我們體系的醫院裡 似乎沒有收治這麼一位患者
Why were you searching for that patient?
為什麼你要調查那位患者？
It must have been that Dr. Takeda guy.
一定是那個叫武田的傢伙查的
What is it you're planning this time?
你這次又在打什麼主意？
If this operation succeeds,
如果這次手術成功
I will without a doubt win the chairman election.
我一定會贏得理事長選舉
That means that your mentor,
那樣的話，你所敬仰的佐伯教授
Dr. Saeki, will lose.
可就輸了
That's why I'm trying to help you, right?
所以我才說我要來幫忙
Let's get this done together, okay?
一起加油吧
Great Doctor Nishizaki.
西崎大醫生
At the same time, a new patient named Ryuichi Kobayashi
這時，一位叫小林隆一的患者
was admitted suddenly, jumping ahead of a long line of patients
突然入院，插隊眾多
waiting for an operation from Dr. Saeki.
等待佐伯教授手動術的患者
I'm honored to have Dr. Saeki as my operating surgeon.
能讓佐伯醫生替我做手術是我的榮幸
Dr. Tokai will be taking care of you until next week's operation.
在下週手術之前 這位渡海醫生將負責照顧你
He's a man I trust.
他是我很信任的醫生
That's very reassuring.
那真是讓人安心
-I'm going out for a bit. -I see.
-那我出去一趟 -好的
Pardon me.
失陪了
Dr. Saeki hasn't been around here much lately.
教授最近好像經常不在
Maybe he's just sick of work and playing hooky.
可能受夠了工作，出去偷懶了吧
What are you saying? Of course, that's not it.
您在說什麼，才不會是這樣
Don't you think it's odd he's not here?
這種時候不在，不是很奇怪嗎？
Track him down.
去查一查
What?
什麼？
Find out where he's going.
確認一下教授去了哪裡
Follow him.
跟蹤他
Are you going today as well?
您今天也要去那邊嗎？
Please let me go with you.
請讓我跟您去吧
I'll be fine by myself.
我一個人就行
Or are you worried about something?
還是你有什麼不放心嗎？
No.
沒有
Are you sure it's a good idea to be tailing him?
跟蹤教授真的沒問題嗎？
No, but Dr. Tokai told me to do it.
不，但渡海醫生要我這麼做
He thinks Dr. Saeki is skipping out on work.
他認為佐伯教授翹班去偷懶
I want to prove that's not true.
我想證明他說錯了
-Thanks for coming with me. -Well…
-謝謝你陪我來 -不客氣
I just finished my shift so it's fine.
我正好也下班了，所以沒關係
But I don't think I'll be of much help.
不過我可能幫不上什麼忙
That's not true.
別這麼說
I need another witness.
我還需要其他人作證
And it's shady if I do it alone.
而且自己跟蹤感覺很不光明磊落
With the two of us, we can say we're on a date or something.
兩個人一起的話 還能說我們在約會之類
-A date? -What?
-約會？ -什麼?
No, not like that. It's just an excuse.
抱歉，不是那個意思，只是個藉口
-An excuse? -That's right.
-藉口？ -對
I see.
我知道了
I mean…
我是說…
I… it doesn't have to be an excuse…
也不一定要是藉口…
Dr. Sera!
世良醫生！
Oh, no.
不會吧
What? We lost sight of him.
什麼？已經跟丟了
-You wasted time saying weird stuff! -Sorry.
-都怪你說些奇怪的話 -抱歉
I can't do it. Dr. Tokai has got me in a funk.
不行了，渡海打亂我的心情
Can't we take him off the team?
能不能把他踢出團隊？
Take Dr. Tokai off the team?
把渡海醫生踢走嗎？
I'm the surgeon in charge.
我是執刀醫生
He is just an assistant, but I can't let him take my glory.
他只是個助手 但我不允許他搶走我的鋒頭
There's one other problem.
還有另一個問題
Aren't there any other candidate patients?
還有其他病患人選嗎？
I've been searching for a low-risk case, but I haven't had much luck.
我有在找一些簡單病例，但很難找到
They're all too risky.
風險都太高了
They were all scheduled to be operated on by Dr. Saeki.
每個患者都預定由佐伯來做手術
He's trying to make me fail with a high-risk case.
他打算用疑難雜症讓我們手術失敗
His oldest trick in the book.
這是他的一貫伎倆
Dr. Tokai joining the team
讓渡海加入手術團隊
is likely a ploy to prevent me from succeeding as well.
可能也是為了在正式手術時妨礙我
-I don't think he would-- -You know what's at stake, Dr. Takashina.
-他應該不至於會… -高階，你應該心裡有數
If we fail, you'll lose your place at Teika.
要是手術失敗 帝華大學就沒有你的位置了
Find me a patient.
快點找合適的病患
And while you're at it, find a way to get rid of Dr. Tokai.
然後找藉口把渡海弄走
Show me your worth.
有點用處吧
Get it done.
把事情搞定
Where's Dr. Sera today?
世良今天不在嗎？
On a date.
去約會了
What?
什麼？
What about you? Are you sure you're okay?
那你呢？你這樣可以嗎？
Neglecting the Caesar.
放著凱撒的事不管
I would like to talk with you since we're both on the team.
既然我們同一個團隊 我想跟你聊兩句
Is the great Dr. Nishizaki telling you to kick me out?
是西崎大教授要你設法弄我走嗎？
You always obey your superiors.
你對上司還真是言聽計從
It's to ensure the proliferation of the Snipe and Caesar.
這是為了讓醫狙和凱撒變得普及
It is what I believe in.
這是我的信念
Up until now,
渡海醫生才是吧
you never showed any interest in new technology, until now.
你之前一直 對最新的醫療器械興趣缺缺
What has changed?
這次為什麼態度變了？
I don't like robots but this time,
我是不喜歡機器人什麼的
there's someone I dislike even more.
但是這次有個傢伙讓我更討厭
Are you talking about Dr. Saeki?
是指佐伯教授嗎？
I'll cooperate this time.
這次我會合作
And yet up till now you've always done as he said. Why?
你一直都那麼順從他，又是為什麼？
I don't understand what you believe in.
我實在搞不懂你的信念
I don't believe in anything.
我這個人沒什麼信念
The only thing I believe in is myself.
我只相信自己
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
-Kobayashi's exam results are here. -Thanks.
-這是小林先生的檢查結果 -謝謝
Move it.
礙事
This is…
這裡是…
Sakura Hospital.
是櫻花醫院
I see. About Kobayashi?
這樣啊，小林先生的事嗎？
It wasn't mentioned in the handover, but what kind of patient is he?
交接事項裡沒說 請問是怎樣的患者？
A special case brought in by Dr. Saeki.
好像是佐伯教授介紹來的
It's top secret, so be careful.
是最高機密，要謹慎處理
Mitral valve insufficiency disorder?
二尖瓣閉鎖不全嗎？
It's a light case. He could be perfect for the Caesar trial.
因為症狀比較輕 應該很適合用凱撒來治療吧
He's scheduled for surgery by Dr. Saeki.
已經決定了由教授動手術
We already have three candidates for the trial.
而且臨床試驗已經有三個人選了
Well, well. Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生，您來啦
-Mind if I drop by? -Not at all.
-介意我過來嗎？ -不會
Let's go to the examination room.
請移步檢查室
Did he just say examination room?
他剛才說檢查室嗎？
Yes. Maybe he's not feeling well.
對，也許是哪裡不舒服
Scalpel.
手術刀
It's almost operation day. Still no other optional patients?
很快就要動手術了 還找不到其他患者嗎？
There is one patient named Kobayashi.
有一個叫小林的病患
He has been scheduled for surgery with Dr. Saeki.
但是已經安排由佐伯教授來做手術了
-Then we'll take the patient from him. -But--
-那麼從佐伯那裡搶過來吧 -但是…
If we can use that patient, I can prove that the Caesar
如果能治好那位患者 我就可以證明凱撒
is far more effective than Dr. Saeki's black forceps.
優於佐伯的黑色止血鉗
If it's a low-risk patient,
而且如果是低風險的病例
we won't need that Dr. Tokai either.
那也不需要渡海的幫忙
Dr. Takashina.
高階醫生
Show your worth.
立點功吧
Got it? Your worth.
知道嗎？立點功
So where did he go?
所以他跑去哪裡了？
To Sakura Hospital.
去了櫻花醫院
It seemed like he was there for an examination.
好像是去做什麼檢查
-Sakura Hospital? -Yes.
-櫻花醫院？ -對
So…
那個
About his last operation,
教授上次動手術的時候
I thought I saw him tremble for a moment.
我好像看到他的手抖了一下
Do you think he might be ill?
他會不會是生病了？
It's his heart.
是心臟吧
His heart?
心臟？
-Dr. Takashina. -Hello.
-高階醫生 -你好
About Dr. Saeki…
佐伯教授他…
Is that true?
是真的嗎？
Great Doctor Nishizaki would be happy to hear about it.
大醫生聽到了一定很高興
Yes.
是的
He will.
沒錯
So go tell him.
那快去告訴他啊
-Dr. Saeki has heart problems? -That's what Dr. Tokai said.
-佐伯醫生心臟有問題嗎？ -渡海醫生是這麼說
Didn't you say you saw an X-ray photo with a pair of forceps inside a heart?
之前你不是說有看到 心臟插著止血鉗的X光照嗎？
I did.
對
What if that X-ray…
如果那張X光照…
was of Dr. Saeki?
是佐伯教授的呢？
I'll find an opportunity to look for that X-ray.
我抽空去找一下那張X光照
Could you try finding the data for me?
你能幫我進資料庫查一下嗎？
Sure, I can try.
好的，我試試看
SAEKI
（佐伯）
-Yes? -Did you find it, Dr. Sera?
-你好 -世良醫生，找到了嗎？
I can't find it anywhere. You?
完全找不到，你呢？
I tried searching Dr. Saeki's name.
我用佐伯醫生的名字檢索過了
There's no X-ray and no trace of any information at all.
完全沒有X光照，連病歷沒有
Not even a check-up?
連病歷都沒有嗎？
-I'll keep looking. -Okay.
-總之，我再找找看 -好
The name Tatsuji Iinuma was searched.
那個人查詢飯沼達次這個名字
Wait a second.
等一下
Yes?
怎麼了？
Would you mind looking up Tatsuji Iinuma?
你能用飯沼達次這個名字 再查一次嗎？
Tatsuji Iinuma?
飯沼達次嗎？
Yes, just in case.
對，以防萬一
Got it. I'll call you back later.
知道了，查完了我再回電給你
NO RESULTS FOR "SEIGO SAEKI"
（佐伯清剛，查詢無結果）
TATSUJI IINUMA
（飯沼達次）
Nekota.
貓田護理師
What are you doing here?
你在這裡幹什麼？
Um, you're always sleeping in Dr. Tokai's room, right?
那個，貓田護理師 你總是在渡海醫生的房間裡睡吧？
Did you ever come across an X-ray photo?
你有看過X光照嗎？
In the photo, there is…
上面有…
-a pair of forceps-- -What is this about?
-止血鉗 -你到底想說什麼？
Miwa.
美和
I don't know what you're looking for.
雖然我不知道你在查什麼
But if you get in Dr. Tokai's way,
但如果妨礙到渡海醫生的話
you'll be crushed.
你就會被毀掉喔
Great. These all seem like good candidates.
很好，這些患者看起來都是好人選
Yes.
是的
Whoever is chosen,
無論選誰
you'll be able to operate in ideal conditions.
都能在理想狀態下動手術
Got it.
知道了
Anything else?
還有別的事嗎？
Do you think he might be ill?
他會不會是生病了？
It's his heart.
是心臟吧
-No. -Very well.
-沒有 -那就好
Let's figure out which patient we'll choose.
我們一起想想要選哪一位患者吧
Please stay on top of it.
麻煩你多留點心
Right.
是
A case of a doctor neglecting his own health?
身為醫生反而不注意健康嗎？
A cardiac surgeon with a bad heart. How ironic.
心臟外科醫生的心臟 居然有問題，真諷刺
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
By the way, I've been wondering about this Kobayashi, a new patient.
對了，我對那個叫小林的患者 一直有個疑問
While he does need surgery, it doesn't seem very urgent.
他的確需要動手術，但感覺不是急症
A light case.
是輕症
And yet he was suddenly admitted.
但他卻被突然送來住院
Playing favorites, are you?
給他特別待遇
It's a favor for a friend.
因為是朋友請託的
Another thing, how is the Caesar operation going?
對了，凱撒手術的事怎麼樣了？
They've decided on a patient named Kudo.
好像決定要選那個叫工藤的病患
I will be there as well,
反正我也在
so I'm sure it'll succeed.
一定會成功的
That means that I'll lose the election for chairman.
這表示我會輸掉理事長的競選
I don't care. Don't hold back. Give it your best.
沒關係，不用客氣，盡全力去做吧
But remember this, Tokai…
但不要忘了，渡海
No matter how great the Caesar may be,
不管凱撒是多麼優秀的器械
in the end, it's people.
最後還是要靠人
Man always prevails.
人總是更勝一籌
The fateful day finally arrived.
就這樣，決定性的那天終於到來
Why didn't you tell Dr. Nishizaki about Dr. Saeki?
佐伯教授的事 為什麼你沒告訴西崎教授？
I'll tell him when the operation is complete.
我會在手術完成後去報告
No matter where we all stand,
不管我們的立場是什麼
we must think of the patient.
都必須考慮病患
Having Dr. Tokai on the team is our best option.
我認為有渡海醫生在團隊裡 是最好的選擇
It's a decision based on what I believe in.
我是根據我的信念而做出的判斷
What you believe in?
信念嗎？
TEIKA UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL
（帝華大學附屬醫院）
The wonder of the Japan-made Darwin
奇蹟般的國產達爾文機器人
will finally be revealed to all of Japan.
終於要在全日本亮相了
Indeed.
確實啊
I hear there will be a welcome message from Dr. Saeki during the broadcast.
聽說佐伯醫生也會在轉播期間致詞
-That's right. -I'm looking forward to it.
-是的 -我很期待
Certainly.
是
Please excuse me.
失陪
We're about to start. What is it?
馬上就要開始了，什麼事？
We have a problem.
出問題了
We can't find Dr. Saeki anywhere.
到處都找不到佐伯教授
-What? -No one has heard from him since morning.
-什麼？ -從今天早上就失聯了
He's supposed to give a greeting before the operation.
手術前教授要致詞的
If he doesn't show up,
要是沒出現
it will leave a bad impression on the board members.
會讓理事們留下很差的印象
There's another thing.
還有一件事
We kindly ask that you wait in the family waiting room
請您在家屬等候室等待
until the operation is complete.
直到手術結束
We'll keep you updated.
我們會通知您消息的
-Thank you. -Please excuse me.
-拜託了 -我先走了
Well, well. Dr. Saeki.
佐伯教授，您來了
Why is the director from Sakura here?
為什麼櫻花醫院的院長會來？
He's that Kobayashi's dad.
他是小林先生的父親
Well, well. Thank you for caring for my son.
小犬承蒙大家的關照
Our pleasure.
您客氣了
Today is the day. I'm counting on you to help my son.
今天小犬就拜託大家了
Today?
今天嗎？
Didn't you hear?
你沒聽說嗎？
For today's joint operation with Teika,
今天跟帝華大學的合作的手術
they've chosen Kobayashi.
選定了小林先生
What?
什麼？
But why?
為什麼？
-Hey! What's going on? -That's what we want to know.
-喂，怎麼回事啊？ -我們也想知道
Dr. Kurosaki told us.
黑崎醫生告訴我們了
He said that he showed you the patient's chart before.
他之前他給你看過那位患者的病歷
You were kicked out of Teika,
你表面上說被帝華大學掃地出門
but you've been working with Dr. Nishizaki all along?
卻一直背地裡替西崎教授辦事？
That's dirty.
太卑鄙了吧
The patient was scheduled with Dr. Saeki. To snatch that away is--
那位患者已經決定由佐伯教授動手術 把人搶走真的是…
-You're wrong! I did no such thing! -Then who did?
-你們弄錯了，我沒有 -那是誰做的？
Me.
是我
Dr. Tokai…
渡海醫生
I received a request from Dr. Tokai this morning.
今天早上我接到渡海醫生的委託
I've explained the trial to Mr. Kobayashi and received his approval.
我跟小林先生解釋過試驗 也徵得他的同意了
Why did you do this?
為什麼要這麼做？
We're starting the preparations! Please hurry!
要開始準備了，動作快
Hear that?
聽到了沒？
-Hey. -Camera.
-喂 -攝影機
To our audience at Teika University.
各位蒞臨帝華大學的來賓
Today, I am honored to present to you the surgery that will mark the completion
今天我非常榮幸能展示這場
of the domestically produced Darwin known as Caesar.
證明國產達爾文凱撒機器人 研發成功的手術
We had originally planned for Dr. Saeki
我們原先安排了佐伯教授
to make an appearance this morning, but his whereabouts are currently unknown.
今天早上出面致詞 但他現在去向不明
It would seem the doctor has been dealing with serious heart problems.
教授他似乎有嚴重的心臟問題
His heart?
心臟？
The board members are watching. He shouldn't say that!
當著理事們的面說這種話不好吧
Today's patient was originally scheduled for surgery with Dr. Saeki.
本次的患者原本預定 由佐伯教授來動手術
But the doctor is in no shape to operate.
但教授的身體狀況實在不允許
Instead,
所以
for the patient's safety,
為了病患的安全著想
it was decided to change to surgery performed by the Caesar.
我們決定改用凱撒進行本次手術
That explains everything about the current situation.
原來是這麼一回事
I'm worried about Dr. Saeki,
雖然我們也很擔心佐伯教授
but for the patient's sake, I'm glad we have the Caesar.
但對患者來說，幸好有凱撒
This patient's surgery was carefully rehearsed and simulated
為了這位患者的手術 帝華大學的醫療團隊
by Teika University's brilliant staff.
一直進行操練與模擬
I would like to perform today's operation with the same staff.
我希望今天也跟同一組人進行手術
Which means we'll be asking you all to leave.
所以請你們所有人離開
Dr. Tokai. Thank you for the helpful information.
渡海，感謝你的寶貴消息
But that is a different matter from this surgery.
但這是兩碼事
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
-You too. Out. -What?
-你也出去 -什麼？
This is Teika University's surgery. Performed by doctors from Teika.
這是由帝華大學主導手術 由帝華大學的醫生執刀
It's none of Tojo University's business. That means you, too.
跟東城大學或你沒有任何關係
And so, once again,
那麼接下來
we will now perform mitral valve repair surgery
我們開始使用國產達爾文凱撒機器人
with the Japan-made Darwin, Caesar.
進行二尖瓣修補手術
Now it's entirely a Teika University surgery!
這樣不就是變成 帝華大學專屬的手術了嗎？
As if they are solely responsible for the Caesar's success.
好像凱撒的研發都要歸功於他們
It's a fact that Teika completed it!
本來就是我們帝華大學完成的
How dare you!
說什麼啊？
Stealing our patient and the credit too?
不止是搶病人，連功勞也要搶嗎？
First, we'll make an incision in the pericardium.
首先，切開心包膜
You told them everything about this patient, and about Dr. Saeki's health…
你把患者的事 和佐伯教授的身體狀況都說出去了
Why?
為什麼？
I have to take down Dr. Seigo Saeki.
為了拉下佐伯清剛
There was something I wanted to confirm too.
我還想確認一件事
-Confirm? -That guy on the screen there.
-確認？ -螢幕上那個傢伙
His plan was to get rid of you all along.
一直打算把你踢走
-Anything else? -No.
-還有別的事嗎？ -沒有
There was no need
信念這種東西
for what you believe in.
一點用處也沒有
But you were removed from the team too, Dr. Tokai.
但是渡海醫生你不也被踢出去了嗎？
Yes, I was.
是啊
In the end, it's people.
最後還是要靠人
Man always prevails.
人總是更勝一籌
Anyway.
算了
Wake me up when it's over.
結束後叫醒我
Pericardial incision complete.
心包膜切開完成
Next, we proceed with myocardial protection.
接下來開始準備心肌保護
Dr. Nishizaki is very skilled even with a robot.
西崎教授的操作技術真是一流啊
Aortic occlusion.
阻斷主動脈
-Right.
-是
-Clamping forceps. -Here.
-阻斷鉗
Not these.
不是這個
Bring the forceps that Dr. Nishizaki always uses.
把西崎教授的常用手術鉗拿來
-What are you doing? -Hurry up!
-你在做什麼？ -動作快
They seem to be in a rush.
好像有點手忙腳亂
A Darwin surgery is a team effort. It's not just the operating surgeon.
達爾文手術需要團隊合作 不止是靠執刀醫生的技術
The assistant following up with the robot's arm is crucial.
負責機械手臂的助手也很重要
But they don't have the experience.
但他們缺乏經驗
-What are you doing? Hurry. -Yes, sir.
-幹什麼呢？快點 -是
Clamping complete.
完成阻斷
Okay.
好
The left forceps is not in their line of sight.
左邊的手術鉗已經不在視線範圍內了
-What? -This is not good.
-什麼？ -情況不妙
The aorta has sustained damage!
主動脈受到損傷
-Compress the bleeding area! -Suction! Now!
-壓迫出血點 -抽吸，快點
Right!
是
-Adding volume! -Okay!
-增加容量！ -是
Take over!
快拿紗布來！
This is really bad.
情況真的很不妙
-Hurry! -We need gauze, quick!
-快點 -把紗布拿過來！
What are you doing? More suction!
幹什麼？快點抽吸啊
It's no use! It won't stop!
不行了，血止不住
Damn it.
可惡
Hey, get out of here!
喂，滾出去
Unskilled doctors are better off dead.
醫術差的醫生去死算了
But I'll keep you alive for now.
不過現在還是留你一命
What?
什麼？
I told you, didn't I?
我不是說過了嗎？
It will be fine as long as I'm here.
只要有我在就沒問題
I'll stop the blood.
我來負責止血
You carry on.
你繼續手邊的工作
Finish the Caesar operation.
完成凱撒手術就好
It will be your win in the end.
這樣你就可以獲勝了
Congrats, Chairman.
恭喜你，準理事長
This mistake of yours…
你的失誤…
I'll make it all disappear.
我會處理掉的
-Nekota. -Yes.
-貓田 -是
Move it.
閃開
Move it!
閃邊去
-4-0. -Here.
-4-0縫線 -這裡
Dr. Saeki…
佐伯教授
-Professor! -Dr. Saeki.
-教授 -佐伯教授
Let me take over, Dr. Tokai. This is a joint operation.
換我來，渡海，這次是聯合手術
If Dr. Nishizaki won't operate, then I will.
既然西崎教授不再執刀 那麼換我接手
Is that okay?
可以吧？
Tokai, I said I would take over.
渡海，我說換我來
Move it.
讓開
I'll take over now.
我來吧
Okay.
是
-Get this out of the way. -Right.
-把這個搬開 -是
I'll do a minor thoracotomy and suture the injured area to stop the bleeding.
立刻進行小型開胸手術 並縫合傷口止血
Removing clamp. Flow down.
解除阻斷，降低流量
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -是
Dr. Takashina, Dr. Sera, help me.
高階和世良過來幫忙
-Electroscalpel. -Here.
-電動手術刀 -是
-Thoracotomy device.
-開胸器 -這裡
-4-0. -Okay.
-4-0縫線 -是
-Metz. -Here.
-手術剪
Blood pressure…
血壓…
stabilized.
穩定了
Next, we'll perform minimally invasive beating heart mitral valve surgery.
接下來進行 微創心臟不停跳二尖瓣手術
-Scalpel. -Here.
-手術刀 -是
Professor…
教授…
Who said he was in no state to operate?
是誰說教授狀態不佳？
His skills are incredible.
他的醫術太精湛了
-Metz. -Right.
-手術剪 -好
-Black forceps. -Okay.
-黑色止血鉗 -是
This is Tojo University!
這就是東城大學
This is the pride of Tojo University! Operating Surgeon Dr. Saeki!
最引以為傲的佐伯式手術
Operation complete.
手術完成
You finish up.
你來收尾
Okay.
是
Did you think I would lose so easily?
你以為我會這麼輕易輸掉嗎？
This is me.
這就是我
These are the black forceps.
這就是黑色止血鉗
I…
我…
haven't lost yet.
還沒有輸
My assistant just made a mistake operating the arms.
只是助手操作機械手臂時失誤
You people…
你們這些人
You're all fired!
全部開除
Throwing people away like that…
那樣把別人一腳踢開
You have no right to be saving people.
沒有資格拯救病人
-A job well done! -Great work!
-做得好 -太棒了
Incredible!
好厲害！
Doctor, thank you very much.
醫生，謝謝您
-I didn't do anything. -That's not true.
-我什麼也沒做 -哪的話
I heard my son's operation was a success.
聽說我兒子的手術進行得很順利
I can rest easy.
我總算可以放心了
Mr. Kobayashi.
小林先生
You're the head of Sakura Hospital, right?
你是櫻花醫院的院長吧？
Finally, it all makes sense now.
這樣就說得通了
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
The reason your son was admitted suddenly to our hospital.
你兒子突然來我們醫院住院的理由
For you to be able to ask that of Dr. Saeki,
你可以直接拜託佐伯教授
you must share a special bond.
想必你們關係匪淺吧
To pay us back,
不過你也要付出代價
I want you to inspect Dr. Saeki's heart.
你得幫教授檢查心臟問題
Dr. Saeki's heart?
心臟？佐伯醫生嗎？
Oh, you haven't heard?
怎麼，你不知道啊？
Then why was he visiting your hospital?
那麼教授為什麼要去你的醫院？
There's a patient that Tojo doesn't want anyone to know about.
因為東城大學 有一位患者不想曝光身分
That's why he kept visiting your hospital.
所以他才一再去你的醫院
He was barely able to see the patient today.
他今天差點來不及回來看病患
Who is it?
他是誰？
What are their symptoms?
有什麼症狀？
How old are they?
多大年紀？
What's their name?
叫什麼名字？
-You better spit it out. -What are you doing?
-你最好快說出來 -你幹什麼？
Tell me.
快說
-Tell me! -Dr. Tokai, what are you doing?
-快告訴我！ -渡海醫生，你做什麼？
Move it.
礙事
Tell me.
告訴我
Say it!
快說
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯醫生
Tell me!
告訴我！
Iinuma…
飯沼…
Tatsuji Iinuma…
飯沼達次
Are you okay?
您沒事吧？
Dr. Tokai!
渡海醫生
It's Dr. Saeki!
是佐伯醫生
It finally happened?
終於發生了嗎？
What is this? Forceps left behind?
這是什麼？遺留的鉗子嗎？
Even so, he'll save them no matter what.
就算是這樣，他還是會救人
Don't underestimate me, Tokai.
別低估我，渡海
Sometimes there are things more important than life itself.
有時候，有些事比性命更重要
What is research to you?
研究對你來說代表什麼？
Wasn't it made to save people's lives?
不就是為了拯救人命嗎？
You are the shame of Tojo University!
你是東城大學之恥！
Dr. Saeki can't be saved.
佐伯教授沒救了
Please save the professor!
拜託救救教授！
He's always saying crazy things and making me do as he pleases.
他老是亂說話，對我頤指氣使
Move it!
少礙事
I'll kill him.
我要殺了他
Subtitle translation by: Tom Grathwol
字幕翻譯：莊雅婷